Xavier RUCAHOBATINYA



Born

18/02/1994

Contact

Address:

Kigali/Rwanda KN 275 st

Phone:

+250785209432

Email:

rucahoxavi@gmail.com

Languages

Kinyarwanda – very good English – good

SUMMARY

web developer and software developer based in Kigali/Rwanda. I studied computer science at secondary school and I am studying computer and software engineering at university (UR-College of science and Technology). I experienced in HTML (5), PHP, Python (Django), JavaScript(node.js), CSS, Bootstrap, SQL and NoSQL DB.

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- Project management
- Version control with Git
- UI/UX
- Front-End Development
- Back-End Development
- Test-Driven Development
- Continuous Integration

EXPERIENCE

Java Desktop Application developer - 2017 to 2020

Web Developer - 2016 to 2020

Participant at Andela Kigali Bootcamp - 2019

- Create Repository on GitHub for the challenge.
- Write all the features story on pivot tracker.
- Create every feature UI one after another.
- UI design with HTML, CSS and JavaScript (without any framework).
- Write all the features API story with pivot tracker.
- Create every feature API with node js and data structure.
- Create every feature API with node js and PostgreSQL database.
- API Test with postman.
- Write all API tests with mocha & chai
- Push it on GitHub.
- Integrate with Travis ci, Coveralls and code Climate.
- Deploy on Heroku.
- Generate API document (Postman).

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Python
- Java
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- MYSQL
- Firebase
- SQLite
- > jQuery
- Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

Bachelor: Computer and Software Engineering – 2014-2020(pursuing)

Secondary School: Computer science(finished).

CERTIFICATES

https://drive.google.com/file/d/13SbjiqM KupSFmdqZskND9ZIT07ehAzT/view?usp=sharing

REFERENCE

https://github.com/Rxavio